Benjamin D. Killeen

Ph.D. Student, Johns Hopkins University
Department of Computer Science
3400 N Charles St
Baltimore, MD 21218, USA
killeen@jhu.edu

Summary

A Ph.D. Student at Johns Hopkins University, I am interested in intelligent surgical systems trained in dynamic simulated environments for X-ray image-guided procedures. I am a member of the Advanced Robotics and Computationally Augmented Environments (ARCADE) research group and the Computational Interaction and Robotics Laboratory (CIRL).

Education

Ph.D., Computer Science, Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, MD, USA.

08/2019 - present With Mathias Unberath and Gregory D. Hager.

B.A., Computer Science with Honors, Minor in Physics, University of Chicago, Chicago, IL, USA. 09/2015 - 06/2019

Thesis: Starting from Scratch: Deep Learning for Novel Scientific Image Analysis

With Gordon Kindlmann.

Research Experience

Research assistant, Department of Computer Science, Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, MD, USA. 08/2020 - present With Mathias Unberath, Gregory D. Hager.

Research Assistant, Laboratory for Computational Sensing and Robotics, Johns Hopkins University, 08/2019 - 06/2020 Baltimore, MD, USA.

With Gregory D. Hager, Mathias Unberath, and Russel Taylor. Recipient: LCSR Fellowship for Outstanding Incoming Ph.D. Students.

For our county-level dataset in [M-1].

Research assistant, Department of Computer Science, University of Chicago, Chicago, IL, USA. 03/2018 - 08/2019 With Gordon Kindlmann.

Professional Experience

Computer Vision / Al Intern, Applied Research, Intuitive Surgical Inc., Sunnyvale, CA, USA. 06/2020 - 07/2020 With Omid Mohareri.

Software Development Intern, Cognitive Computing, Epic Systems, Verona, WI, USA.

06/2018 - 08/2018

Research Intern, IBM Research - Almaden, San Jose, CA, USA.

06/2017 - 08/2017

With Geoffrey Burr.

Selected Honors

Best Presentation, Reliable Software Systems course, Johns Hopkins University, USA.04/2021Best Graduate Project Award, Computer Integrated Surgical Systems and Technology course, Johns Hopkins University, USA.05/2020COVID-19 Dataset Award, Kaggle.04/2020

Intuitive Surgical Best Project Award, Deep Learning course, Johns Hopkins University, USA.

12/2019
Project: Enriching Unsupervised Feature Learning via Intermediate Subtasks.

With Michael Peven, Shaoyan Pan, and Matthew Pittman.

Publications

My publication list is also available on Google Scholar. Unless otherwise noted, (*) denotes equal contribution.

Peer-reviewed Journal Articles

A. Hundt, **B. Killeen**, H. Kwon, C. Paxton, GD Hager. "Good Robot!": Efficient Reinforcement Learning for Multi-Step Visual Tasks with Sim to Real Transfer. IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters, vol. 5, no. 4, pp. 6724–6731, Oct. 2020. doi: 10.1109/LRA.2020.3015448.

S. Ambrogio, P. Narayanan, H. Tsai, R. M. Shelby, I. Boybat, C. di Nolfo, S. Sidler, M. Giordano, M. Bodini, N. Farinha, **B. Killeen**, C. Cheng, Y. Jaoudi, G. W. Burr. Equivalent-accuracy accelerated neural-network training using analogue memory. Nature, vol. 558, no. 7708, p. 60, Jun. 2018. doi: 10.1038/s41586-018-0180-5.

B. D. Killeen, Shreya Chakraborty, Greg Osgood, Mathias Unberath. Toward perception-based anticipation of cortical breach during K-wire fixation of the pelvis. SPIE Medical Imaging, to appear 2022.

J-2

1-1

- Selected for **oral** presentation.
- J. D. Opfermann*, **B. D. Killeen***, C. Bailey, M. Khan, A. Uneri, K. Suzuki, M. Armand, F. Hui, A. Krieger**, M. Unberath**. Feasibility of a Cannula-mounted Piezo Robot for Image-guided Vertebral Augmentation: Toward a Low Cost, Semi-autonomous Approach. IEEE International Conference on Bioinformatics and Bioengineering (BIBE), to appear 2021.
- *Joint first authors; ** joint last authors.
- Honored with Best Paper Award in Bioengineering.
- X. Liu*, B. D. Killeen*, A. Sinha, M. Ishii, G. Hager, R. Taylor, M. Unberath. Neighborhood Normalization $for \ Robust \ Geometric \ Feature \ Learning. \ Proceedings \ of \ the \ IEEE/CVF \ Conference \ on \ Computer \ Vision$ and Pattern Recognition, 2021.
- *Joint first authors listed alphabetically.
- C. Gao, X. Liu, W. Gu, B. D. Killeen, M. Armand, R. Taylor, M. Unberath. Generalizing Spatial Transformers to Projective Geometry with Applications to 2D/3D Registrationc. MICCAI, 2020, arxiv:2003.10987.
- X. Liu, Y. Zhang, B. Killeen, M. Ishii, G. Hager, R. Taylor, M. Unberath. Extremely Dense Point Correspondences using a Learned Feature Descriptor. Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition, pp. 4847-4856, 2020.
- **Preprints**
- J. Y. Wu*, B. D. Killeen*, P. Nikutta, M. Thies, A. Zapaishchykova, S. Chakraborty, M. Unberath. Changes in Reproductive Rate of SARS-CoV-2 Due to Non-pharmaceutical Interventions in 1,417 U.S. Counties. medRxiv preprint, Jun. 2020, doi: 10.1101/2020.05.31.20118687.
- B. D. Killeen*, J. Y. Wu*, K. Shah, A. Zapaishchykova, P. Nikutta, A. Tamhane, S. Chakraborty, J. Wei, T. Gao, M. Thies, M. Unberath. A County-level Dataset for Informing the United States' Response to COVID-19. arXiv preprint, 2020, arXiv:2004.00756.
- Patents G. W. Burr and B. D. Killeen. 2020. Efficient Processing of Convolutional Neural Network Layers Using
 - Analog-memory-based Hardware. 20200117986, filed March 25, 2019, and issued April 16, 2020, uspto.report/patent/app/20200117986.

Selected Press

Dziarkach, Andrei. "Details with Andrei Dziarkach." Voice of America. November 21, 2020 Accessed November 26, 2020. golosameriki.com/a/detali/5671254.html.

Rosen, Jill. "Dog Training Methods Help JHU Teach Robots to Learn New Tricks." The Johns Hopkins University Hub. The Johns Hopkins University, October 26, 2020. hub.jhu.edu/2020/10/26/positivereinforcementfor-robots.

Teaching

Supervision

I have supervised a number of talented masters and undergraduate students on research projects and

Sean Darcy, Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, MD, USA. 10/2021 - present Zidi Tao, Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, MD, USA. 10/2021 - present Nethra Venkatayogi, The University of Texas at Austin, Austin, TX, USA. 05/2021 - 10/2021

Max Judish, Brown University, Providence, RI, USA. 01/2021 - 08/2021

Shreya Chakraborty, Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, MD, USA. 08/2020 - 09/2021

Philipp Nikutta, Technical University of Munich, Munich, Germany. (Now at Argo Al.) 12/2019 - 03/2020

Assistant Teaching

Computer Integrated Surgery, Department of Computer Science, Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, 08/2019 - present MD, USA.

With Russ Taylor and Emad Boctor.

Machine Learning and Large Scale Data Analysis, Department of Computer Science, University of 03/2019 - 06/2019 Chicago, Chicago, IL, USA.

With Yali Amit.

Wrote supplementary course material and held weekly lab sessions.

Selected review: "Ben was incredibly patient during office hours and always responsive to student questions. In addition, he often presented demos during office hours or showed easier ways to handle the homework assignments; both were very helpful."

More reviews available at benjamindkilleen.com/teaching/2019-spring-lsda

Grading

Department of Computer Science, University of Chicago, Chicago, IL, USA

01/2019 - 08/2019

C-4

C-3

C - 1

M-2

M-1

P-1

2020

- Scientific Visualization
- Introduction to Computer Science I
- Introduction to Computer Science II

Tutoring Mentor, Polygence. 06/2021 - present

Topics in Computer Science, Machine Learning, Baltimore, MD, USA.

We have covered topics such as differential calculus, neural networks, computer vision, natural language

processing, and functional programming.

Service Family Member, Thread, Baltimore, MD, USA. 06/2021 - present

 $I\ volunteer\ with\ students\ at\ Douglas\ High\ School\ in\ Baltimore\ City,\ helping\ with\ homework\ and\ fostering$

personal connections.

Graduate Student Committee Representative, Laboratory for Computational Sensing and Robotics, 09/2020 - present

06/2020 - present

Baltimore, MD, USA.

Head of Student Resources

Volunteer Instructor, CompileHer, Chicago, IL, USA.

Peer Review - IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR) 2021

- Nature Scientific Data 2020

Selected Coursework

Graduate Vision as Bayesian Inference GPA: 3.82

Reliable Software Systems Theory of Computation Parallel Programming Nonlinear Optimization II Computer Integrated Surgery II Computer Integrated Surgery I

Deep Learning

Undergraduate Unsupervised Learning* GPA: 3.81

Computer Vision

Machine Learning and Large Scale Data Analysis

Operating Systems Honors Combinatorics Honors Algorithms Honors Discrete Mathematics

Scientific Visualization
Programming Languages
Networks and Distributed Systems
Quantum Mechanics I \& II
Intermediate Mechanics

Electronics Wizards

*Graduate level.

 Memberships
 IEEE Graduate Student Member
 2020 - present

Extracurricular In my spare time, I enjoy climbing, running, and making visual art. I also write creatively:

Creative nonfiction: benjamindkilleen.medium.com

Science fiction.

Metadata This document is available

- online: benjamindkilleen.com/markdown-cv.

- as a PDF: benjamindkilleen.com/files/cv.pdf.

Created based on markdown-cv by Eliseo Papa with styles based on David Whipp.

MIT License.

Last updated: November 2021